You were making like 36,000 a month
recurring within your first 4 months.
>> Yeah, that's wild.
>> And it was just us, so that was great.
We're sending about 120,000 letters a
month now. I didn't expect this. In
2024, we broke the 5 million mark. Last
year, we broke seven. The best way to
describe it is something you've never
heard of, but your mother's going to
love. Is Mother's Day huge for you?
>> It's our Super Bowl. Yeah, that's
awesome.
>> What other niches do you think could be
really interesting with the snail mail
business?
Would you believe that you can make
millions of dollars per year sending
stories through the mail? Well, that's
exactly what Michael and his wife Hanny
do with the Flower Letters. They charge
12 bucks a month and they are sending
$120,000 letters per month. Last year,
they made $7 million in revenue. But
what's most impressive is that within 4
months of starting the business with
almost no money, they were making
$36,000 a month. And most of that was
profit. They grow the business through
Facebook ads and referrals. And I am
just obsessed with the snail mail
subscription business. This is the
second episode I've posted about it in
the last two months. We'll link to the
one I did with Hannah below. And at the
end of this episode, Michael will give
us advice for starting our own
subscription business. What niches look
interesting, how we can be successful,
and most importantly, how to find
customers. Let's dive in. You want to
start by just telling us who you are and
what you do?
>> Yeah. Michael Clark. I'm the co-founder
and CEO of a company called The Flower
Letters. The best way to describe it is
something you've never heard of, but
your mother's going to love. So, we tell
stories through letters sent through the
mail. You get two letters a month for a
year and it tells a story. My wife is an
artist and an author and uh just so
creative. She sings, she does
everything. She's doing stained glass.
>> I call her her creator. And it was a
about February, March of 2020. Anyway,
we were just talking. We were on a walk
and uh she was trying to figure out how
to kind of she she made these paintings.
She incredible these 3D floral paintings
and she put one up for sale and it sell
within you know 20 minutes. I remember
one night we we were going on a date and
she put one up and it was like 3 hours
past. She's like, "Hey, this hasn't sold
yet. Do you think it's not good?" I'm
like, "Hey, I got to put this into
context for you. You sell your paintings
in 3 hours." Like, yeah, most people
have paintings up for days, months,
years. People are they want your stuff
and then sure enough in 30 minutes
someone buy it.
>> And what was she selling these for and
on what platform was she selling them?
>> Oh it's just Instagram. She just
>> okay
>> make a panty put it on Instagram say hey
if you want it let me know.
>> Someone would say I want it. And uh you
know depending she make anywhere from
this size to to big. I mean the big ones
could be upwards of $1,000 but there's
mostly small ones. So a couple hundred
dollar each each way.
>> Yeah. And so she was doing that just and
you know really enjoying it. And then
she was trying to figure out how to grow
her business and kind of get more people
involved in email list and and uh she
had the idea. She's like what if I like
sent them a letter if they sign up for
my email list? I like that's kind of a
expensive thing to sign up for email
list. You send them an email. She's like
what if I send them a letter? She's like
there's all these old letters you can
find. To be honest with you, all at once
the idea came to me and I saw people
like I remember getting mail a letter in
the mail. I saw people going to the
mailbox getting a letter and it being a
chapter in a story. And I said, "Man,
what if you what if you wrote a story
and sent it to them?" And she's like,
"That's a terrible idea."
Christiey's a writer. And so there's a
lot of details we had to work out. But I
was like I was like immediately I
thought of World War II. I was like what
if what if you write a letter then I
write a letter and we kind of send that
out and we've kind of figured that out
and we just iterated went back and
forth. There was another subscription
that we were doing called letters from
afar. We actually did a podcast with
them. They're they're awesome. We got
their letters and there's a sort of a
standalone letter each month which is
like
>> okay
>> great model like do the standalone
>> and you you were a customer of this
you're saying at the time?
>> We subscribed to it.
>> Okay. And so we had been getting these
letters. I like what if that was a story
like and so you know letters from afar
is a big part of our origin. We talked
to them and and they're they're a great
great company. I highly recommend them.
Uh they're I think they're more geared
towards kids but they follow this a
character around the world. It's really
fun.
>> Their models it's it's much simpler than
telling a story. Figuring out okay what
does this look like? How many letters do
we send every month? It was like, "It's
going to be a year and it's going to be
24 letters and we're going to send two a
month." To be honest, when we looked at
I was like, "Hey, this will be kind of
fun. This will be cool. This will be uh,
you know, let's uh let's give it a
shot." I'm still working on my startup.
I was doing some consulting and uh we
originally started she wrote a letter. I
actually in her first story I there's a
letter that I wrote,
but it became clear like I'm not a great
writer. She is. She's a great writer. So
like okay. She's like, "You know what?
I'm going to take this. I'm going to
write this." And so, she's like, "I'm
going to write this." I was like, "Oh,
sounds good." We started doing Instagram
posts and just figuring things out.
>> Just through her own friends and family,
not like from a big business page or
anything.
>> No, we just we started a flower letters
Instagram, put it out. And one of my
things as a entrepreneur is I when I
tell people I said, "If you're launching
a product or service, don't tell your
family and friends. They'll give you a
false positive. your mom's not your
mom's gonna buy 10 of them, but she's
not your customer.
>> You gotta find your customer. We just
put it out there.
>> 33 people signed up. I was like, "Okay."
>> And what was your first pricing?
>> $12 a month
>> for two letters. You got two letters and
one month for 12 bucks a month.
>> 12 bucks a month. And then uh
>> and your cost is I mean a dollar, stamp,
envelope, paper, and then time.
>> The paper everything just to get
everything in at the volume we're doing.
And it was more around $2 to $3 cuz we
put a lot of things. We put a lot
inside.
>> Nice stationery and stickers and
>> nice and Okay.
>> And we've done that and that's sort of
what sets us apart. You can get a lot
and I can show you some things if you
want but but yeah costs were relatively
low. It goes really well. We started
dabbling in ads. So our our main sort of
acquisition was through Facebook ads and
that's what really started to kind of
get us traction.
>> Facebook ads on both Facebook and
Instagram.
>> Yep. Yeah. Facebook and and it was us
just like giving it a try. We knew
nothing about Facebook ads. And then
this guy that I was working with, this
kid really, I was talking to him about
what I do and he's like, "Hey, I want to
try that." I was like, "Okay,
>> try the flower letters business or ads?"
>> He wants to try doing ads and marketing
with us. I was like, "Okay, okay,
>> that's fun."
>> I was like, "Let's let's go for it." And
uh anyway, he like I remember by the end
of the year anyway by the end of the
year we had a few thousand people that
decide that and then he pitched me on
coming and working for me full-time. I
was like, "Oh,
>> okay."
>> Okay.
>> He started running your ads pretty early
on.
>> Yeah, probably around October. So, we
launched in like August. We started we
sent our first letters in at the end of
August and then Yeah. October, we
started dabbling in ads, just spending a
few bucks here and there and people
started showing up. And and then one of
the things that was really important
that I'm surprised how many businesses
don't invest in is email. We knew from
the get-go that email is really
important because Meta can break. You
know what if it goes away? You know it
goes down. You got your email address.
So early on we started trying to acquire
email addresses and so we can connect
with people that way.
>> How did you do that? Was that with ads
as well?
>> Yeah, ads would kind of come people
would come to our website. That's the
first sort of on-site funnel is you ask
for their email address for a discount.
>> Pretty standard e-commerce acquisition.
That's actually turned out to be huge
for us.
>> Upwards of 38 and sometimes, you know,
40 even sometimes 50% of our revenue is
email driven.
>> Wow.
>> Anyway, if you're an entrepreneur and
you're not thinking email, think email.
>> You have to. Yeah. Own your audience.
>> You got to know it. Since then, we've
we've we're at 3.5 million letters
mailed. We're sending about 120,000
letters a month now. We've got six
stories
>> concurrently.
>> More coming. Yeah. So, six stories, but
nine subscriptions you can sign up. One
of them is a fantasy. And so, there's
seven parts of it. There's three parts
currently. So, eight. I should say
eight. There's eight options that you
have right now. Most of it historical
fiction. And we're called the flower
letters. And so that was part of the
formula is at the beginning it was all
of our heroins have a flower name.
Originally we're going to do historical
fiction which is the predominant story
line for us but then we have Norah Aan
who's a fantasy and actually was super
popular and it's been been tons of fun.
It's it's one of my favorites. But that
Norah Aan's been part of our marriage.
Like she's been writing that since she
been building that world since we were
first married. So, but yeah, it's been
wild. Just wild ride.
>> Believe it or not, just because you're
watching this doesn't mean you're
subscribed to my channel. YouTube's
going to show you stuff even if you're
not subscribed to it. Over half of
people that watch my videos are not
subscribed. It would mean the world to
me if you just hit subscribe. Thank you
so much.
>> So, first year you said you finished at
2 or 3,000 customers. Was that the end
of 2020 or your first full 12 months?
>> Just the end of 2020 within five month
four months. Yeah. So, end of year we
had about 3,000 customers.
>> You were making like 36,000 a month
recurring within your first four months.
>> Yeah.
>> And it was just us. That was great.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It was simple.
>> What was your cost per acquisition on
your ads in those early days? Like how
much were you spending to acquire a
customer?
>> Early days. If we could go back preio,
>> it was like 20 bucks. 15 maybe 20 bucks.
>> Okay. So even on a subscription, we
could be profitable within three months,
right? And that's one of the biggest
challenges with a subscript subscription
like this, which I think probably people
that are getting into it are learning.
The key to our growth has been the
prepaid option
>> like a year up front.
>> Yeah. Paying up front. It's been
interesting in this what we do. It's
kind of like, oh, this is they're sort
of they are buying a full story and it
is a subscription, but like it's really
not traditional subscriptions like your
typical. was like, "All right, I'm going
to pay 12 bucks and you send me a
supplement." Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> Or, you know, or some of these other
letters, it's like, "I'm going to, you
know, give you $8 and you're going to
send me one letter and it stands alone."
With us, it's like
>> for this to work, you have to get every
letter and you have to get every letter
in order.
>> And so, thinking about that, I mean,
that's what makes it complicated. And
across now stories, we're like, "Oh,
yeah.
>> All right." You know, I think when I
step back and look at it, that has been
our key to our growth and success is
adding more stories, being able to kind
of service a customer as they are, any
story they would like, get them their
letter, you know, soon.
>> Now, I have to think with churn, with
losing customers, you're I'm assuming on
the story ones, your churn is low
because they want to know what happens
at the end, right? So, this is a
business built. It's a business built
for very low churn. Y
>> but I imagine if you do get churn it's
going to be after the first couple weeks
or month because maybe the story just
doesn't resonate and then after that if
you keep them after that you probably
keep them for all 12 months.
>> Yeah.
>> Is that pretty accurate?
>> One of the things that makes our turn so
low as well is that we're a very
giftable item.
>> Oh yeah.
>> They can't cancel for themselves, right?
Like someone gives it to them
>> sometimes. It's funny. We have the best
customers. They're incredible. But like
I never thought of this happening. It's
like uh someone had to reach out. I was
like, "Yeah, my mom said she hated it. I
need to cancel." I was like, "Whoa, your
mom that's
ow." And I was like, "Okay, that's
that's fine." So she, you know, uh, so
they'll start getting it like I don't
like it. So that'll happen from time to
time and that's great. To me, the mail
is a miracle. I love the postal service
because of like how well it is.
Sometimes I get a bad rap. It's like ah,
the postal they lost my letter. It's
like
>> you talk to a kid this now. You tell
them like, "Hey, you can put this piece
of paper in this box.
>> It'll show up in Russia in a few weeks."
They're like, "Whoa."
>> Yeah.
>> Wow. Right. They can understand
sometimes their mind works like I can
send a text and get it to Russia right
now.
>> How does that piece of paper get to
Russia or to who even the next state
over
>> one of the things? So, what sort of
prompted me to leave everything like I
was a fintech guy, software, let's build
a tech company, you know what I mean?
But what sort of drove me into leaving
all of that behind and focusing solely
on this one was the opportunity. I think
the growth, it was the impact. We
started getting letters like very early
on year one from people saying that
they, you know, how grateful they were
for us because we're doing this because
it's something to look forward to. I
won't say her name, but I remember her
name. Uh she would keep it on her
bedstand because she had this just I
think it was fibromyalgia. She's just in
pain all the time. He's like, I look at
that letter and I know another one's
coming and it just keeps me going. Like
I'm reading these things. I'm like, I
didn't expect this. I did not expect
this. And we get these every week. We
still get them of people having a very a
very positive impact. And so
>> I stepped back, looked at what we were
doing and said, "Okay, if we can truly
run a business together, my wife and I,
we love each other and we really like
working together." Which I'm finding is
unique. She does the art, I do the
business. We step back and say, okay,
how can we have the maximum impact in
this business and grow it so that we can
bring this light and joy to people's
lives? And so I left every thing behind
and we focused solely on this and uh we
we configured and the best way to
describe it because there's you know
there's a lifestyle business then
there's you set up and it's like this is
you know I've got 10 different things
going on or there's like the
generational thing and we decided this
was going to be a generational thing for
us that we want our grand to work here
with us that caused us to configure a
little differently
>> and reinvest pretty much everything back
in the growth back into the the learning
the marketing, the customer acquisition
early on. I mean, it's been fantastic.
So much fun, but so hard. Oh, man. You
know.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I was going to say I had a
shipping business and we shipped
hundreds of thousands of packages. And
anytime I hear someone say like X, Y, or
Z got lost in the mail, I'm just like
no, it didn't. Like statistically
speaking, no, it did not. Cuz we almost
nothing that we sent didn't arrive. Like
it always arrived.
>> Yeah. So it is miraculous how that
works. So your churn is excellent. What
is your churn on a percentage basis? And
how has that changed over time if at all
or across different genres or stories?
>> Last I looked globally, we're probably
at like a 5% churn.
>> Monthly or yearly?
>> Yearly. So very very low.
>> That's incredible.
>> We predominantly do uh sell our prepaid
option. People are way much less likely
to turn in the prepaid. We make it very
attractive to come into the prepaid.
What is the price for that compared to
12 a month?
>> 12 a month. So, right now you can do
prepaid for $100.
>> It's like eight and a half bucks a
month.
>> Yeah. So, that was our entry point. So,
and then you can add, you know, a 10 to
it. The 10 has been just so
wellreceived. People love it. They're
pretty. You can maybe see one right back
here.
>> Oh, yeah. Would you mind holding one of
those up? They get that like with the
first so they can store everything in
it.
>> Yeah, they store the letters in it.
>> Brilliant. So looking across, we we're
relatively inexpensive comparatively to
other subscriptions, but that's because
we want to make it accessible for people
because of the impact. We want to have
as much impact as we possibly can.
>> But we have other products that help,
you know, from a profitability
standpoint, like the 10 different
things. Like why haven't we added a
letter opener? It's like, man, that's
like a no-brainer.
>> It just takes time to figure that out.
You could put it in the tin. No,
>> put it in the tin when you ship it.
>> I mean, there's so much stuff we can put
in the tin, like letter opener, post
cards, stickers, like different things
they can add to their order if they
want.
>> So, it's it's 10 bucks. Do they have to
pay for additional shipping for the tin
as well?
>> So, the tin we sell the tin for 30.
>> Oh, you said 10, not 10. Okay.
>> Yeah. So, then it'll be, you know, $8
shipping, $8, $9 shipping. Right now,
we're doing free shipping. Spring
promotion is going into Mother's Day.
So, and then standard shipping. If you
do the letters, uh, we started charging
more shipping, okay?
>> Because we start to track when we can at
the volume that we, you know, when we
get into kind of busy seasons, we'll do
free shipping just to remove any any
barriers to entry. So,
>> yeah. Is Mother's Day huge for you?
>> It's our Super Bowl. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. It's It's bigger than Christmas.
>> Wow. Is it more, you know, sons and
daughters for their moms or husbands for
their wives?
>> It's daughters for the mothers.
>> Interesting. More than anything. more
than anything
>> and friends for friends.
>> Our demographic is uh is pro is female
35 plus and probably skewing a little
bit older. or so starts at 35 then kind
of gets into like the 45 55 is kind of
the peak and it's ah I love this market
so much when I think they're underserved
when you interacting with them they're
they're the best customers I've ever
worked with like across all
>> they're reasonable they're forgiving
they're
>> you know and they they they they're like
oh yeah you know that's okay and if
they're upset you call them and they're
like oh you know that's okay you know
we'll figure it out and our mantra is,
hey, we're always going to do everything
we can to make it right and to do right
by you. Cuz what we promise something
that is pretty it's a pretty tall order
to fulfill, you know, something to look
forward to. It's a story that continues
and, you know, go comes in order. When
that doesn't go well, it's kind of like
we didn't we didn't get we didn't make
it happen. So, we got to do whatever we
can to make that right.
>> Especially when it's a gift.
>> How long are the letters? How many
words? And cumulatively, how many words
is the whole series? And have you ever
thought of making that just into a
physical book?
>> Physical book. Uh, we have, but at the
same time, no.
>> Cuz you want to keep it special to the
letters, right? Or else they're just
like, "Oh, I'm paying 100 bucks for a
book."
>> I'll tell you one of the things that we
didn't do early on is make each letter
formulaic. You know, I think if you're
>> I see what you mean. If you're a, you
know, if you're thinking of starting
this, you're like, "Okay, every letter
is going to be two pages with a postcard
and maybe one little insert and that
happens every single time." That's
great. It's very predictable and that's
a good model if it works. One of the
things that I think has helped us that
makes us people like us is it's
different. Like one letter, you're gonna
get eight things and you're gonna have a
four-page letter. And then the next one,
you're gonna have a two-page letter and
a postcard and like a sticker to the
point where there there was one where we
had to do something because people kept
reaching out. I was like, did I get
everything?
>> It's like, yeah,
>> it's just the one we sent you before.
There's tons of stuff
>> and uh I can go in one for
>> Yeah, I'd love to see it. How many words
are each letter on average?
>> I don't know.
>> Okay. It's just not something you track.
>> Well, that's another thing with Hy is um
and we have we we try to work into it is
writing a story in this way is an art
form. It's that that she's perfected
because there's so much that you can do,
you know, with different content. I know
this is just a random letter from Lily
Clara, but I'll kind of give you an idea
of what comes in this one. So, this is
the letter.
And so when she's creating this, she's
like curating the experience, if that
makes sense.
>> And she's like, "Okay, in this letter,
this in this envelope, there's going to
be a letter, and this is three pages."
So the front and back.
>> Mhm.
>> And then on this one, then there's this
is like an advertisement card. It's from
the era.
>> Oh, cool.
>> This isn't part of the story. It's just
like, let's send them this so they can
be drawn into
>> Yeah. And that's a real ad from that
era.
>> Real ad. Yeah,
>> that's cool.
>> American Machine Co. Ice cream freezers.
Pretty cool.
>> Yeah,
>> there's one that we were sending that
ended up being that we didn't really
notice it, but it was offensive, so we
pulled it.
>> Okay. Oops.
>> And then there's this one she designed.
This is a bookmark.
>> Wow. And she's designing all of these?
>> All of it? Yeah. This is a And there's
like some silver like metallic stuff on
it. This is a character from the story,
actually. Then there's um a telegram. So
this is the telegram part of the story.
So like
>> and it's like you look at it's like a
telegram can fill in a lot of gaps,
right?
>> And then there's postcards. So I read
there's 12 postcards in every story that
you get.
>> Okay.
>> And so we send these
>> one per month.
>> Yeah. About one one a month
>> ish.
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> How long did it take you to quit your
job?
>> Oh
>> your startup.
>> Oh man, that was hard cuz that was like
you I loved it so much. We were we
started right during the pandemic. In
fact, he's a business partner from then.
He's killing it now with AI.
>> Mhm.
>> And it's still going. It was It took me
about a month to kind of truly really
decide. And it was January of 2021 where
I I went to him. I was like, I got to I
got to go do this. I got to, you know,
do this. And he was supportive and
great. Haven't looked back. Haven't done
anything else. This takes all my time.
It's it's awesome. Today it's been six
years going on six years. Yeah, almost
six years. And what is your monthly
revenue and profit today?
>> Monthly revenues varies monthtomonth
across it. It's about in 2024 we broke
the 5 million mark in in total revenue.
>> Wow. Wow.
>> And then last year we I was like, man,
maybe we could go to 10.
>> And it's like, well, hold on, Clark.
That's double.
>> That's hard. That's hard. Last year we
just we broke seven.
>> That's still
>> And so this year, hey, what what about
10? And it's like, hold on, Clark,
that's a lot.
>> Yeah.
>> Still a lot.
>> After Mother's Day, you'll be like 12
for sure.
>> Oh,
>> and then come October, you're like 10
would be nice.
>> We'll see. We'll see. I you know I have
this I have a goal the next I mean the
next goal is a 10 million mark just
because that's sort of a a benchmark but
if we can match what we did last year
I'd be thrilled because we were able to
service you know so many c new customers
and uh that's been been a lot of fun. So
our month that's one of the the biggest
challenges of this business is the
seasonality. So you have these big peaks
in Mother's Day and you have to figure
out okay
>> Mhm. We've got to make sure we've got
enough operations to go then to get to
the next one and continue to invest. And
so, real quick before we keep going, I
just wanted to share this with you. If a
customer calls you right now and you
don't pick up, what happens? They call
the next guy. You don't get a missed
call notification from a lead that you
never knew existed. That sale is now
gone. There's a tool that fixes this.
It's a business phone system called Quo.
Everything lives in one inbox. Calls,
texts, voicemails, notes. Your whole
team sees what's going on with every
customer so nothing slips through the
cracks. Quo also has an AI agent called
Sona that picks up calls 24/7 when you
can't. It qualifies leads, sends
follow-up texts, and books appointments
all without you lifting a finger. And
now Sona can transfer calls to
teammates. If the AI can't handle
something, it'll just route the caller
to the right person instead of just
taking a message. You can even set up a
custom call tree so callers get routed
to the right person instantly. So
whether it's just you or a small team,
your business sounds like it's been
running for years. 90,000 businesses
already use Quo today and you can try it
free at quo.com/tko20
and get 20% off your first 3 months with
my link link in the description as well.
And now back to the video. That's been a
lot of learning for us, especially
because we're we didn't configure this
to be lifestyle driven for us. So, we
haven't extracted cash from the
business. We we tried to invest all of
this. So, we try to keep our net profit
as low as we possibly can from a tax
perspective and keep the business
growing, keep it fueled, and try to with
the intention of expanding our our net.
>> Yeah, we're hitting a critical mass, I
think, where we're really poised to
really start to expand into different
categories like retail. Retail is a real
opportunity, I think, for what we do. We
figured out a really neat product where
we worked I don't know if you've been
ever been back to the Newport Mansions
in Rhode Island.
>> They approached us last year. One of
their the person that runs their gift
shop signed up, reached out like, "What
if we what if you wrote a story about
the Gilded Age and we could put it in
our shops?" We were like, "Yeah, that's
totally cool." So, we're in their shops.
That's that's pretty awesome.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, then we're like, "What if we
could get this? What if you could walk
into Costco and you see the flower
letters on a on a stand and you know
it's a gift a giftable thing. It's like
a gift almost like a gift card that come
in and
>> Yeah. You just bring it to the register.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So we built out a whole redemption
website and
>> Wow.
>> And you know where you can come in, you
scan a QR code,
>> pulls up, you enter your address and
you're good to go. And so that's been
built out and configured and uh we'd
love to, you know, get into retail
stores, but also expanding into
different mediums, audio, we've always
explored what if we could have the
opportunity to turn this into like a TV
series.
>> Yeah, why not? Why not a podcast where
your wife just reads the letters?
>> Oh, we we thought about that. We we have
a podcast. We're sort of dabbling in it.
It's called Stories Told Through You.
People from our community come on and
tell their stories. Like come to find
out people have like people are
fascinating. That's one thing I've
learned about this community from them.
I had this experience where I was in the
doctor's office and you know this lady
had a little
>> a post-it note right on her desk and I
was you know paying for my doctor visit
and her post-it note was like taped down
you know. So one of those post-it notes
like she's like I'm going to look at
this every day. It says your story
matters. And that like that hit me. I
was like, why would you think your story
didn't matter? And so anyway, our we we
invite people from our community to to
come on our podcast. We've heard some
fascinating stories. Just incredible.
>> Yeah. And everyone has them.
>> I don't care who you are, your story is
fascinating because you're human. You
felt fear. You felt love. You felt
betrayal. I mean, all of these things
that make up a great story are part of
your life. It's been fun to extract that
and have people come and tell their
stories. So, but yeah, that's a great
idea. Like an audio version where she
reads the stories. Man, there's so many
different things.
>> So, if you were like taking profits out
of the business, what would you hope to
do in net profit on 7 million in
revenue?
>> If we didn't invest back into as much as
we did in in Meta
>> Mhm.
>> You know, I would love at some point to
be able to have a net profit of a
million dollars.
>> Yeah. Your growth would slow.
>> Yeah. It would it would slow. we
wouldn't be able to get,
>> you know, as much as many customers. But
there is a point, there is a tipping
point where I think we we start to hit a
more organic
>> Yeah.
>> growth. A lot of people referred this to
their friends. With more people coming
into this medium and and doing telling
stories through letters, there's a lot
of people that have started to do it in
the last last little while. It's
becoming, I think, a viable, I think,
um, way to experience a story. And I
think with that, you know, we we we've
never really invested in organic growth
until it's all been paid. But as soon as
we're able to crack organic and not have
to spend so much within meta, that's
when net profits will will start to to
really build and grow.
>> How much are you spending on meta today?
>> Oh, so last year we spent 2.6 million.
>> And your cost per acquisition went from
15 to 20 in the early days to what
today?
>> Oh, yeah. Oh man, if we could do 15 to
20, we'd be swimming in it.
>> Yeah.
>> But it's I mean every every e-commerce
brand has I mean you can't do it. You
can't do that. That's impos it's
virtually impossible. Some do. Yeah. I
mean just you know because they're
they're really good at it. But ours is
40 to 50 at this point.
>> Did you hear my episode with Hannah the
snail mail business?
>> I heard part of it. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. She's been
>> So she's all or organic.
>> Yeah. You should go look at her Tik Tok
page and like the style of video that
she posts because there's a lot there's
a lot to learn there. She's doing it
really interestingly.
>> Yeah, I'm learning that organic what you
do is an art.
>> I don't know
>> cuz you go you're I don't imagine you
spend a lot on ads for what you do but
you have a huge audience.
>> Depends on the thing.
>> You've been able to kind of get out and
make it happen. But every time I see
it's like uh figuring out the organic
would become a full-time thing because
when I look at it it's like well what
what organic there there could be some
organic approach because we're a product
right we're not a lot of the organic
success or or brands that are organic
the people are the product in a lot of
ways
>> where people are buying them when they
buy their product because they like
their content they enjoy their you know
what they are and they they've
they've attached themselves so closely
to the brand that when you buy their
product, you're you're essentially
buying buying them. And so that would be
essentially me and Hy really investing
in that organic approach, which we
thought a lot about like she's writing
stories like that. That's what she does.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know. There's lots of things we
could do to try to figure that out. But
the more I I look into the organic and
see the people who are successful in it,
I'm like, "Wow, they've really kind of
because it's not just, you know, I
really appreciate when they do because
it's not just a willy-nilly. It's like
formulaic."
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> You figure it out. You know, exactly.
You know your hook, you know everything.
And it's it's what what I do.
>> But it starts willy-nilly.
>> Yeah.
>> And you learn from there.
>> You figure it out. You're like, "Hey,
wow, they like that. Okay, I'll do
that." Yeah, let's do more of that.
Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> So, roughly, I'm just estimating here,
you're spending like a third of your
revenue on like cost of goods sold,
postage and paper and supplies. You're
spending another thirdish on meta ads
straight to meta. And then the rest of
it is going to pay your people
>> operations over investing growth
operation. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's a it's a reinvestment cycle,
but just been fun, right? But it's kind
of a cuz you can see opportunities,
different ways you can
>> Mhm.
>> can grow and it's no nothing's ever
different. Like every year's, you know,
exciting something else is happening.
New stories are coming out. Like a lot
of it goes into investing in new stories
to be honest. Researching the stories,
things like that. But yeah, that's kind
of that's where we're at.
>> So your yearly turn is 5%. You know,
$100 per year per customer. How long I
mean it's still early. You're five and a
half years in. How long are customers
staying? What's your like year-over-year
churn or like lifetime value, I guess?
What's the lifetime value of a customer?
>> 12 months. Lifetime value right now is
about $180
>> from across 12 months. Really?
>> 12 months? Yeah.
>> Wow. Why not closer to 100 if they're
paying
>> two? 12 bucks a month. Okay.
>> They sign up for one story.
>> So, you'll have a customer, and this is
not uncommon. They see our ad like, "Oh,
wow. I'm going to gift this to my mom
and to my sister so that I too. And
then, you know, later on they're like,
you know what? I'd like to do this. And
they buy it for themselves.
>> So now that person has spent, you know,
upwards of $300 depending on what
>> how many they do a tin or whatever.
>> But we have a lot of repeat purchasers.
I saw one some someone bought like 10
for their friends and I was like, man,
we
>> that's crazy.
been incredible.
>> How do we get more of those?
>> Yeah.
>> Because you still spent 40 or 50 bucks
to find that customer, too, you know?
>> Yeah. But it's also we have a really
strong core of people that when we
release a new story, they're excited to
sign up for it
>> because they they love what we do and
they know they they kind of know what to
expect from us. Uh from a story
perspective, we're not trying to be
edgy. We're not trying to like scare
you. We're not trying to like throw
anything in this controversial. The
stories are all designed to be just full
of light, happy endings. You know, we're
not apologetic about that. We're try not
trying to throw any curve balls at you,
but our our customers appreciate that
and really like that.
>> And so, if they're spending 180 per
year, do you know how many are coming
back for a second year?
>> It depends. A lot of it bleeds into the
other because it'll be she'll they'll
buy two and then six months later
they'll buy another one and then, you
know, a year later they'll buy another
one. So we'll we'll we'll we'll have win
back campaigns where people maybe
haven't, you know, been paying
attention, know we have another story,
so we'll do email campaigns to try to
win them back.
>> I think we've built a really good core
of loyal customers now. It it's sort of
hard because it just doesn't renew,
right? It's not like a after your story
is done, you don't just roll into
another one and pay yes. We don't we
>> you sign up individually for each story.
That makes a little bit more challenging
for us to really get subscription data.
I we also don't process our annual
subscriptions through a subscription
software. We kind of do that on our own
and we use a software monthtomonth
>> and so we don't get as much we kind of
get the the software is good because it
gives you more like a subscription. We
treat them a little bit differently
because they're sort of buying that
story, that experience,
>> right?
>> And we don't have to pay 1% to the
subscription for their the prepaid. If
Mother's Day is 10 out of 10 busy, what
is Christmas, Thanksgiving? How does
that compare on a scale of 1 to 10?
>> Oh, they all they all feel 10 out of 10.
>> Christmas can actually be a little bit
more hectic because just from a
personnel standpoint, that's when people
want to go be with their families, want
to and so we have people staffed is a
little bit more challenging. But
Mother's Day usually, you know, goes
really well. Yeah. I think from a
business standpoint, Mother's Day is 10
out of 10. say nine out of 10 for
Christmas.
>> And what does your team look like? How
many people do you have? And
logistically, are you in like a
warehouse? Do you have automation
equipment for stuffing all these or are
people doing that by hand?
>> It's all by hand. So the way that um and
we have a warehouse just over in Oram,
Utah.
>> Right now, our headcount's 16.
>> We've had as many as 25, but we built in
like our operations manager is incred.
He's fantastic. To give you an example
of how efficient he's gotten us, we used
to have like 15 people stuffing 20,000
letters. Now we have five doing
120,000 a month.
>> Holy cow, that's incredible.
>> But yeah, it's very high touch. So
people are handling each and every piece
that you get has come through the hands
of our our team.
>> It's funny. I talked to a lot of
business owners and nine out of 10en
times it's like, "How are you using AI?
How is AI gonna transform your business?
How are you gonna make more money with
AI? And with this business, I'm just
thinking about it and it's like you
don't need AI.
>> No, I use it every day.
>> But then that's a fe Well, I guess you
don't want AI to write your letters. No.
>> Right. No,
>> you're not going to get AI to stuff your
envelopes anytime soon. No,
>> you could use it in your meta ads. But
how are you using AI?
>> So AI has been I'm fascinated,
it would be an AI business. There's tons
of them you can start, but I use it
every day to process thought. I'll, you
know, do analysis on a string of emails
I've received, pull in data from our
Facebook ads and have it run an analysis
on our efficiency, put in our
financials, right? Plug in our
financials, have it do an analysis, and
give us some insight into, you know, how
we're how we're operating. But yeah,
you're right. We wouldn't use it to
write the letters. But I think there's
some that are probably using AI to write
letters, things that they're doing and
generate images. And I think time will
tell how wellreceived AI generated
entertainment is. I do know that the
entertainment industry is
>> I mean they're already using it. They're
already leveraging it. Um
>> yeah,
>> from a writing standpoint. But yeah, for
me it's more of a business intelligence
>> running it, bouncing ideas.
>> Sure.
>> I generated a web page. It took five
minutes and it was pretty good. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. So, I don't think I told you
this, but my wife is in the middle of
starting a snail mail business for
cooking.
>> Cool.
>> Yeah. It It's called uh snail mail
supperclub.com.
>> Nice.
>> And got a couple selfish questions for
you. Sure.
>> And she's starting it cuz she read a
book called Bread and Wine. And she was
inspired to start like a cookbook club
with her friends where they every month
they meet, they all bring their own
meal, you know, appetizers, entre,
desserts around a central theme. like
this month was Greece or Mexico or St.
Patrick's Day, you know, a country or or
a day or a theme
>> and they all kind of have a group chat
and they just bond over it and they
share their food and they dress up all
nice and she has absolutely loved it.
So, she heard my episode with Hannah and
she's like, I could just turn that
business into a snail mail business
where I could write the recipes out and
we could get some artwork done and it's
great for referral marketing because
like we're encouraging groups. Like, so
one person signs up, the chance that
they send it to their seven friends is
much higher. They don't have to. They
could do it themselves, but then they'd
each get a unique recipe. So, there's
kind of some logistical challenges
there. but she's launching for Mother's
Day. And I'm curious like what what
other niches do you think this is that
could be really interesting with the
snail mail business that you're really
not interested in tackling but you see
um opportunity in?
>> Oh, the recipe is interesting. I there's
a friend of mine started a company
called Peachy Recipe. You can
essentially upload your own recipes and
they'll print out a cookbook for like a
family cookbook. Pretty pretty pretty
neat.
>> Oh, cool.
>> Um but yeah, the recipes ones that's
really that's unique and fun. I think
when there's there's a lot of this any
sort of like the pen pal one is
interesting. We have people that I think
there's other pen pal businesses that
that do it. I'm just trying to think
anything that's like a standalone like
once a month thing
>> is way simpler than than getting into
the story business. The story business
it's a much different animal to tackle
because
>> when you have to write a story and
that's difficult
>> recipes and things like that be
interesting. Someone was like, "Hey, you
should do Santa letters." And I was
like, "Huh? That's in our brand." But
some I know there's a couple people that
do Santa letters around Christmas and
they do well.
>> Where hundreds of people are launching,
starting, testing, experimenting with
business ideas that they heard from this
podcast. If you want to go fast, go
alone. If you want to go far, go
together. Check out tkowners.com. We'd
love to have you. What about true crime?
Like there's a business called Hunt a
Killer and they do like true crime
boxes, right? Where you solve a That's
like a $150 million a year business.
That's huge, right? Yep.
>> And so why not take that and put it in a
like a letter form and just a true crime
story or like a puzzle, something to
decode, you know?
>> I think there's one that does it. I
think I saw one that that is doing that
>> good. They proved the model. Yeah, we
can go copy them.
>> What it comes down to, honestly, that
that the reason those companies were so
successful, one, they they knew they
knew their market and they marketed the
heck out of it.
>> It's all meta ads.
>> Yeah.
>> I think you can only go organic in your
business so far.
>> Yeah. Yeah, especially when something's
sort of niche where it's not a mass
market appeal, you're going to need to
advertise and market and brand
>> and develop e-commerce skills. You know,
CRO, like CRO, I didn't even know what
that was.
>> Conversion for the listener, conversion
rate optimization.
>> Conversion rate optimization like
>> getting 3% of people to buy to 3.2% of
people to buy. That that could be a lot
of money.
>> 3.15. That's
>> Yeah, there you go.
>> And it's like it's the craziest stuff.
Hey, let's make this button green.
>> Yeah, let's move it from the left to the
right side of the page.
>> Who cares? Like, why would you care
about that? It's like, well, when you
have 100,000 people come to your website
in in a 5day period,
>> that could be significant.
>> Yeah.
>> The fact that a button's green and
people are more likely to click on it,
it's wild. It's kind of crazy. or if you
learn like Samsung users in Turkey for
some reason like this the checkout
button doesn't load correctly. So
there's so many one-off things and in
aggregate it can really make a big
difference.
>> It's huge. Yeah. If you're an
entrepreneur, you're a business owner,
you probably see people, you know,
coming up in your feed telling you
you're doing it wrong. Uh let me show
you how to do this, let me show you how
to do that.
>> You have to know your business. You have
to know your like if you don't know your
customer none or your business or your
product none of it's going to work. You
got to know who who your customer is.
You got to know how to talk to them.
That's why early on the more someone can
really truly understand who it is
they're selling to and who it is is
their customer, the better off they're
going to be. Because people ask us,
"Well, who's your customer?" It's like,
"Well, anybody with a mom?" It's like,
"Hm, no,
that doesn't work." Well, it's a great
Mother's Day gift. Well, everyone has a
mom, so just market to everybody. It's
like, well, no, there's a specific
demographic. There's a specific type of
person
>> that this will resonate with. Marketing
for us, marketing to men has been it
hasn't worked.
>> It just doesn't work
>> because we don't get it. Men see this
and within in a 30 second. It's very
difficult to get
>> Yeah.
>> I hope I don't sound sexist, but
>> No, no, not at all.
>> They don't think about it.
>> You have to hook them in. You have to
hook them. Ironically, like if a I mean
most of the people that watch this will
be men and by the time they get to the
end of it,
>> they're watching it for business
reasons, but they're probably like, you
know, I'm going to get that from my mom
because they're they're sold. But if
they were to see a video, the same type
of video, you would not hook them in the
first 5 seconds. Oh,
>> you know,
>> it's been super fun to figure out all
that stuff.
>> But it can drive you nuts. It can drive
you wild.
>> There is an 8020 to all of it. You have
to at some point you have to stop moving
pixels, right? Yeah.
>> Well, my last question for you, I want
to be respectful of your time, is if
someone's watching this and they're
entrepreneurial and they want to start
some sort of a snail mail subscription
business, what is some advice that you
could give them that could help them
save themselves a world of pain or hurt
or all that.
>> Know your customer. Know and but also
know what you're signing up for. Um, if
you're doing a story, it's much harder
than doing a standalone monthto month
>> because a story is is uh, you know, you
have to get it right. It has to come in
order.
>> You have to tie it all together.
>> Yeah. Well, first you have to write a
story, right?
>> Mhm.
>> One of the reasons why it works so well
with my wife and I is she's the creator,
right? And I think most people, and I
think it's saw with Hannah, my wife's
name's Hannah as well, but with with the
person you had on your podcast, works
well with us, is she can really focus on
the creative and I can really focus on
the business.
>> Yeah.
>> And when you have a creative venture,
it's very difficult. So authors, that's
why authors and writers and creators
creatives often struggle is because they
just want to create. They want to write.
They want to do this. They want to do
their art, right? which I should do, but
you got to sell it. And so you got to
figure out, okay, now how do we marry
these things together and, you know,
really get a customer base and make a
viable business out of this thing that
I'm creating? Yeah, I think that would
be know your customer, figure out the
business side. And uh if you can have a
partner whether it's a a spouse or a
friend that can handle one side of the
business and you and the creative cuz
it's a it's a creative endeavor, right?
Probably with your wife if you run maybe
to help her run the business side and
she does the creative side of hers.
It' be a match,
>> great match because you can see,
>> you know, you're you're tracking
customer lifetime value, your
acquisition cost,
>> you know, all the different business and
she can focus on ah
>> because that honestly enabling the
creative is cuz that's your that's your
product. I mean, that's the magic,
>> right? That's squaltched in any way,
shape, or form. It's not going to be as
>> as good. But I'd say that I I I don't
think that's just for Snowma. I think
that's for any business.
>> Yeah.
>> Have creative minds and really business
minds that can really help understand
the ins and outs of business. But also I
need you I mean the more you think about
any business
like the creative I think sometimes we
undervalue creativity and the creative
minds in business.
>> I think if people have a hard time
finding or knowing their customer
because I agree that's paramount advice.
Know who your customer is. If you don't
really know how to figure that out, just
start with a customer of one. You,
right? Yeah.
>> My and my wife and I had a conversation
about this snail mail business is she
wanted to take videos of her making all
the recipes and then put a QR code in
there so people could watch how to make
it. And I was like, "Okay, great idea,
but like that's a very big lift. That's
a a lot more of a lift than what you're
currently planning on." And I asked her,
"Would you like do you watch videos of
people cooking when you make meals for
us?" And she's like, "No." I'm like,
well, like, build it out for you. Like,
if you're not likely to do that, then
people aren't likely to do it either.
>> And so, if it's not a big lift, then try
it, but if it is, then maybe just give
it a month or two before you try it. No,
>> that's really actually insightful
because on our when Hannah was creating
our first story, which is Audrey Rose,
she wrote it for her and she wrote it.
It's like, I I'm going to write this for
me and I'm going to curate this so that
it is something that I love. Turns out,
wow, there's lots of different people
they like.
>> Yeah.
>> And now they feel loyal to her because
they're like her. We like people that
are like ourselves. Right.
>> Right.
>> So, it's good business.
>> I think people need to remember the
markets are huge. Like, I think
sometimes it's hard to fathom.
>> Like, just think about 100,000 people.
That's a lot of people. That's a lot of
people. Times that by 10, that's a
million. That's a lot of people. ties
that by that's a lot of people with a
lot of different preferences. And
because you haven't sold anything
doesn't mean the market's not there. You
just have to keep trying. You have to
keep
>> finding it, iterating. And it could be
you try weird things. I don't know. But
like there's there's markets for just
about everything out there. I think a
lot of people get discouraged because
they're like, "All right, got to
launching it and nobody buys." Like,
"All right, didn't work."
>> Yeah. Yeah. I also have a a a theory
that I tried because a business is all
transactional. It's to me it's whether
it's a transaction of you know coming
into a store. I think that's a
transaction. I came into the store for
some reason. I transacted by walking
through the threshold into the store. I
transacted by picking something up and
feeling it. And then ultimately the
final transaction is a financial trans
transaction where they purchase your
goods or your services. number one
leading indicators of a successful
financial transaction is someone giving
you their email address because like
they want to get what you're sending.
There's a way the secret that and if I
were to start another business I would
do this. I would develop a product a
concept idea and I would build a
website. I would put up a a form coming
soon. Here's my product. Here's what I'm
doing. Here's my service. Give me your
email address, stay up to date. If I can
do just run some ads, just little things
here and there, and I can find a pretty
good mass of people that are willing to
transact with me through their email
address,
>> I'll say, "Okay, I think I got something
going here. I think there's there could
be something here."
>> That's a really easy way to like
>> test a market. Sounds easy, but oh, I
got to build a website. It's like, well,
>> that's easier now than whatever, you
know? But anyway, something that's
something that people could could try,
you know, before they really invest
anything.
>> That's excellent advice, Michael. Thank
you for your time. This has been
incredible. Obviously, we can find you
at theflowerlets.com.
Is there anywhere else that we can find
you?
>> Social media, the flowerflower.
But yeah, our website's the best. You'll
find links to all of our uh social media
there. And um you know, obviously you
can sign up for our email list as well.
and and uh hear from us there.
>> Awesome. Thank you.
>> Thank you, man. I really appreciate it.
Great to meet you.
>> Likewise. All right. What' you think?
Please share it with a friend and we'll
see you next time on the Kerner